<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News | SAGID</title>
    <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/category/news/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/category/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/media/icon_huefee54201d62ccde1196a534a2200366_6097_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/category/news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>👩🏻‍🏫 New thesis launched</title>
      <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-11-20-ignacio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-11-20-ignacio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ignacio Castañeda-Rodríguez is a Chilean industrial engineer from the University of Santiago of Chile with research interests in supply chain designing through processes and waste management. His research line is the design of sustainable supply chains through multi-objective optimization, developing not only the economic area, but also the environmental, social, political, and technological dimensions of sustainability, and promoting the development of distributed local scale production and recycling. He has worked on different research projects related to supply chain design and distributed recycling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ignacio earned his Bachelor’s degree of Science in Engineering at the University of Santiago, and also, from the same house of studies, he has a master’s degree of Science in engineering with mention in Industrial engineering, in the scope of optimization and operation research. He won a French scholarship to do a research internship at the University of Lorraine in Nancy (France), where he worked on distributed recycling in the Research Team on Innovation Process (ERPI) at the Lorraine Fab Living Lab (LF2F). In addition, he has participated in different international conferences on the topics of operation research and technology in countries such as Argentina, Brazil, and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a hard-working, responsible, and committed young researcher with competencies in software such as Python, GAMS, and MATLAB for optimization; R, for statistics and big data analysis; SimaPro for Life Cycle Assessments, and Latex for writing. He has received an award for his commitment as a young researcher from the Engineering Department at the University of Santiago of Chile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👩🏻‍🏫 New thesis launched</title>
      <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-10-13-ziadany/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-10-13-ziadany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Ziadany Mayoral Solis, who joined the SAGID+ chair as a doctoral candidate on Monday, October 9th. Her thesis, titled Assessment of the Capacity of Roadside to Provide Ecosystem Services and the Design of Management Plans Focusing on Sustainable Use,is part of Axis 1 and will focus on the interactions between human practices and the ecosystem services provided by roadside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ziadany holds a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in environmental engineering from UASLP in Mexico, where she studied various environmental issues and how to address them. During her third year, she had the opportunity to participate in an exchange program with France, in the city of Lyon, where she improved her knowledge of the French language and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree, she has developed an interest in soil sciences and ecosystem maintenance. She continued her studies by pursuing a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in France, where she deepened her understanding of the relationship between the climate system and the biosphere, as well as climate change. She then returned to Mexico to work on a research project in an arid region of her country. With her team, she explored the agricultural systems of goat herders to develop and advocate for climate change adaptation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is excited to collaborate on this project, as roadside are complex socio-ecological systems whose management can contribute to the provision of ecosystem services and environmental preservation. One of the main reasons she decided to pursue a doctoral degree is her desire to contribute to applied science projects, particularly working on climate change adaptation and mitigation strategies.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
