<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News and events | SAGID</title>
    <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>News and events</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/media/icon_huefee54201d62ccde1196a534a2200366_6097_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>News and events</title>
      <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>👩🏻‍🏫 New thesis launched</title>
      <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-10-13-ziadany/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-10-13-ziadany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Ziadany Mayoral Solis, who joined the SAGID+ chair as a doctoral candidate on Monday, October 9th. Her thesis, titled Assessment of the Capacity of Roadside to Provide Ecosystem Services and the Design of Management Plans Focusing on Sustainable Use,is part of Axis 1 and will focus on the interactions between human practices and the ecosystem services provided by roadside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ziadany holds a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in environmental engineering from UASLP in Mexico, where she studied various environmental issues and how to address them. During her third year, she had the opportunity to participate in an exchange program with France, in the city of Lyon, where she improved her knowledge of the French language and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree, she has developed an interest in soil sciences and ecosystem maintenance. She continued her studies by pursuing a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in France, where she deepened her understanding of the relationship between the climate system and the biosphere, as well as climate change. She then returned to Mexico to work on a research project in an arid region of her country. With her team, she explored the agricultural systems of goat herders to develop and advocate for climate change adaptation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is excited to collaborate on this project, as roadside are complex socio-ecological systems whose management can contribute to the provision of ecosystem services and environmental preservation. One of the main reasons she decided to pursue a doctoral degree is her desire to contribute to applied science projects, particularly working on climate change adaptation and mitigation strategies.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👋 Launch seminar for the SAGID&#43; chair (11/09/2023)</title>
      <link>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-09-13-lancement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erpi-ul.github.io/SAGID/en/post/2023-09-13-lancement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the launch of the chair &amp;lsquo;Support for Roadside Vegetation Management Professions through Comprehensive and Sustainable Management&amp;rsquo; (SAGID+). Through this chair, we aim to develop &amp;rsquo;turnkey&amp;rsquo; tools and methods capable of assessing the sustainability of roadside management practices, contribute to the evolution of eco-responsible behaviors, and integrate the profession of roadside vegetation manager into bioeconomy sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mark the launch of the chair, we are organizing a seminar on the morning of Thursday, November 9th, at the facilities of Noremat (Ludres – 54), bringing together a diverse audience, including elected officials, maintenance professionals, researchers, and students. We would be delighted to have you join us for this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the detailed program for the morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8:30&lt;/strong&gt;: Welcome Coffee &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;9:00&lt;/strong&gt;: Welcome Speech &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;9:15&lt;/strong&gt;: Presentation of the Chair &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;9:45&lt;/strong&gt;: Presentation on Roadside Management &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Roadside Dependencies and Hydro-Sediment Transfers&amp;rdquo; by Romain Reulier (University of Caen) &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Towards More Sustainable Roadside Management - Lessons from the Côtes d&amp;rsquo;Armor Department&amp;rdquo; by Frédérique Morin (Road Maintenance and Operation Department of Côtes d&amp;rsquo;Armor) &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tree-lined Avenues - Pathways to the Future&amp;rdquo; by Chantal Pradines (Allées Avenues Association) &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:00&lt;/strong&gt;: Working Groups on Chair Axes &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workshop 1: &amp;ldquo;First Steps Towards a Decision Support Tool for Roadside Management&amp;rdquo; &lt;br&gt;
Workshop 2: &amp;ldquo;Towards Shared Decision-Making: Experimenting with a Tool for Collective Scenario Building for Roadside Management&amp;rdquo; &lt;br&gt;
Workshop 3: &amp;ldquo;Prospective: Reflections on the Drivers and Barriers for Future Biomass Valorization Sectors of Roadside Biomass&amp;rdquo; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12:00&lt;/strong&gt;: Networking and Refreshments &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
